KATHRYN M. ADDABBO

908-655-6722 ★ <u>kaddabbo@gmail.com</u> ★ <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/kathrynaddabbo</u>
For more detail, visit my personal website: <u>https://kaddabbo.github.io/</u>

Biostatistician experienced with working in a pharmaceutical vaccine research & development capacity with prior exposure in regulatory affairs and neurobiology research. Skilled troubleshooter, accomplished in data cleaning/aggregating, statistical modeling and machine learning.

- ♦ Competencies: R, Shiny, SAS, SQL, Tableau, Alteryx & MS Office
- ♦ Applied Skills: Advanced critical thinking and problem-solving
- **Gifted Technical Communicator:** Outstanding verbal and written communication abilities with proven expertise presenting data to stakeholders

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Biostatistics | Columbia University, Mailman School of Public Health | 2019

Coursework in Biostatistical Methods, Data Science, Probability, Statistical Inference, Longitudinal Data Analysis, Epidemiology & Randomized Clinical Trials

Bachelor of Science, Biochemistry | University at Buffalo, The State University of New York (SUNY) | 2016

Coursework in Biochemistry, Physical, Organic & Inorganic Chemistry, Calculus, Linear Algebra & Differential Equations

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PFIZER: Pearl River, NY 2019 – 2020

Biostatistics Manager | Vaccine Research & Development

- ♦ Assist in statistical support of vaccine assay development, qualification, validation and throughput conducted by the laboratory personnel including the design, development and execution of data collection, analysis and data reports.
- ◆ Develop effective collaborations with scientist, project management staff, as well as other functional groups to support projects.
- ♦ Give biostatistical input in cross project activities such as staff training programs, working procedures, and various departmental operations and initiatives designed to improve efficiency and productivity.

departmental operations and initiatives designed to improve efficiency and productivity.

Clinical Informatics & Analytics Intern | Insurance

HEALTHFIRST: New York, NY

Evaluated the effect of distance from a member's home to their primary care provider's office on their number of preventable admission (PQIs) over a period of two years. Completed using publicly available information from NYC Open Data. Worked on a team to complete descriptive analysis of the opioid abusers in the member population.

HUNTER JAMES KELLY RESEARCH INSTITUTE: Buffalo, NY

2015 - 2016

Research Assistant | Laboratory of Dr. Laura Feltri

Investigated the absence of specific alpha or beta integrin subunits and their effect on the early stages of myelination. Collaborated on a research team and worked independently to perform tests, analyze results and report findings.

- ♦ Completed DNA extraction and polymerase chain reaction
- ♦ Skilled in cell culture techniques (Schwann cells and DRG co-culture specifically) and immunohistochemistry
- Performed mouse sciatic nerve, rat embryo spinal cord and DRG dissections

CELGENE CORPORATION: Basking Ridge & Berkeley Heights, NJ

2013 - 2016

Pharmaceutical Intern | Global Regulatory Chemical Manufacturing & Controls

Assisted with the preparation of documents and protocols necessary for drug trial submission. Updated standard operating procedures and manufacturer impurities information to fit regulatory and compliance needs.

- Drafted change notices and quality overall summaries
- ♦ Produced stability tables to submit to FDA
- Modified and integrated new acquisition drug trial documents with Celgene's regulatory guidelines

2018